# CHARLES VERLEYEN

Passionate about solving problems through data. Google Cloud is my playground. I like to act on the full spectrum of the data journey (from business workshops, design architecture and then implementation). I strive to bridge development with deployment and therefore I like to wear a SRE hat (I am experienced in DevOps, DataOps and SecOps).



#### CONTACT

charles.xavier.verleyen@gmail.com

+32 497 20 16 60

Val des seigneurs 67, 1150, Brussels

charlesverleyen.com

in Charles Verleyen

#### **SKILLS**

**Programming** 

**Pvthon** Rash **Javascript** 

**Operating Systems** 

Linux Windows

Software & Tools

**Google Cloud Data Ingestion** 

(Dataflow - Apache Beam, Cloud Functions, Cloud Run, Pub/Sub, ...)

**Transformation** 

(BigQuery, Airflow, SQL, pandas, numpy ...)

Visualisation

(Data Studio, Looker, PowerBI)

(Terraform, Github, Gitlab CI, Spinnaker)

**Atlassian** 

**Kubernetes** Docker Office

**Agile Project Management Supply Chain Management** 

**Corporate Finance** 

French **Spanish English** 

# **GOOGLE CLOUD**

- Professional Data Engineer
- **Professional Cloud Architect**
- **Professional Cloud Security Engineer**
- **Professional Cloud Developer**
- Professional Cloud Devops Engineer
- **Professional Cloud Network Engineer**
- Professional Machine Learning Engineer

#### **WORK HISTORY**

🛗 Jul 2020 - Present

Fourcast by Devoteam - Brussels

🛗 Jan 2019 - Jul 2020

Fourcast - Brussels

m Dec 2017 - Dec 2018

**♀** Fourcast - Brussels

III Jul 2015 - Feb 2017 **Q** CTA group - Antwerp

Heb 2015 - Jul 2015

🛗 Jan 2014 - Jan 2015

**♥** Kempinski - DR Congo

Dec 2012 - Dec 2013 General Electric - Mexico **Head of Data Analytics** 

**Google Cloud Lead Architect** 

Google Cloud Data Engineer

Sourcing Manager & BI Analyst

**Project Manager** 

Procurement Manager & BI Analyst

Supplier Quality Engineer

## **EDUCATION**

**Sep 2017 - Nov 2017** 

Data Science Retreat, Berlin

Mar 2017 - Jun 2017

♥ DevLeague, Hawaii

Sep 2006 - Jun 2012 **♀** Louvain School of Management, Louvain

**Bootcamp** in Data Science

**Bootcamp in Web Development** 

BSc and MSc in Business Engineering

## **GENERAL SOFT SKILLS**

Hard worker Perseverance Rigorous Team Player Pragmatic Pedagogic Business acumen Self-learning Simplicity

## **ACHIEVEMENTS, HOBBIES & INTEREST**

- APICS CPIM certificate(5 modules achieved). Obtained in September 2012
- ▼ Vice President of a renowned Junior Enterprise during my studies
- Various volunteer experience in Africa
- Sports enthusiast with active practice of Tennis and Swimming
- ➡ Holder of "PADI Open Water Diver Certificate" and "PADI Advanced Open. Water Certificate"

#### MY IDEAL DAY

